I don't think I've made I I don't think
I made anybody shag lacrosse balls for
me. I I don't think I would have done
that.
>> Okay, so here's your chance to get Alec
back then. What's something you learned
about Alec Pierce that might surprise
some people?
>> He's got some interesting
interpretations of out-of- bounds rules
in golf. I think he's liberal with his
what's a lost ball, what's a No, I'm
kidding. [music]
What's up, Colts fans? I'm JJ Stankovitz
and welcome in to another episode of the
Colts show an Indianapolis Colts
podcast. We are presented by our friends
at Microsoft Surface Copilot Plus PC.
Awesome episode coming up today as we
teased it. Got Daniel Jones, got Alec
Pierce coming on the podcast today.
Great conversations with both of them.
Played a little bit of trivia toward the
end with Daniel Jones. Did one of my
favorite games with him and then asked
Alec a little bit of trivia at the end,
too. Awesome stuff. Let's just get right
to it right now with Daniel Jones here
on the Colt Show.
It is my pleasure to be welcomed here on
the Colt Show by quarterback Daniel
Jones. Daniel, congrats on the new
contract and being able to stay in
Indianapolis.
>> Thanks, JJ. Yeah, excited to be back.
Very, uh, very grateful uh, appreciative
for, you know, the opportunity, you
know, grateful to the Colts
organization, the ERS family and and
Chris Ballard, the coaches here,
everybody. So, uh, thrilled to be back
and and excited to get to work. What
does this stability mean to you to get
this at this stage in your career?
>> Means a lot. Yeah, I feel like um the
last few years have been been, you know,
kind of up and down, but um you know,
really enjoyed being here last year, the
opportunity to come in and compete um
you know, and and uh yeah, very, like I
said, very very grateful um for that
opportunity and and last year um you
know, through training camp, um
competing and wanting to be out there
and then, uh ultimately the faith that
um you know, Chris Ballard and Shane
really, you know, showed showed me and
giving me the chance to play. Um, you
know, very grateful for that. So, means
a lot and, you know, something I take
very seriously. I understand there's a
lot of work ahead and and and a lot of
um, you know, personally to improve and
um, from a rehab standpoint and just
overall as a player and then um, you
know, from a team aspect and making sure
we're ready to go as a group.
>> You mentioned the rehab. Um you you you
said on McAfee that you talked you the
same surgeon as the one who did Tyrese
Hallebertton's
>> Achilles and you kind of talked to him
just what were those conversations like
about just the the you know anything but
the process about recovery just what
were your sort of conversations like
with him? Yeah, I think you know it's
it's helpful to hear experiences from as
many people as you can, especially
someone who's been through uh such a
similar process um you know recently
like like him and and uh you know every
surgeon, every doctor has slightly
different variations on um you know
their rehab protocol you know especially
the initial stages and initial recovery.
So, uh, knowing that he had a pretty
similar, uh, process and and just, you
know, from a mindset standpoint, how he
approached it from a, um, rehab and and
you know, you know, how he set that up
and and where he was and and um, just
just all those things, you know, helpful
to collect as much information as you
can, uh, while also understanding your
your process is going to be a little bit
different and and um, you know, everyone
has slightly different experiences, but
if you can educate yourself and and
collect as much information as you can,
I you know, you're you're in a better
spot to make decisions and and uh kind
of go about your process.
>> How do you compartmentalize the like the
ultimate goal of like rehabbing to get
back on the field, you know, whenever
that may be versus the like dayto-day
grind of it? Like how do you go into
each day of rehab? Are you thinking
about the big picture or is it just like
I have to do this today, this today, and
this today?
>> Yeah, I think that's it. I think you try
to try to make it as uh you know
shortsighted in the you know kind of
while you're on task and while you're um
you know what you need to accomplish for
that day. I think you know there's a lot
of trust in um and your physical
therapists and your your trainers and
fortunately we have great uh physical
therapists here and and trainers um you
know with with Aaron Burril and and Kyle
Davis and and their staff. So, it's
trusting that process, understanding
that if I hit the hit those marks, if I
can do what they tell me to do today,
then um I'll be in a better position
tomorrow to to do that again. And then,
um at some point, you zoom out and see,
you know, how far you've come in a month
or two months or three months and um you
just continue to do that through the
whole process. But I think if you take
too wide a lens initially and try to see
it um you know, you're constantly
saying, you know, trying to see the
whole process and and you know, why am I
not here yet? I think you'll uh you can
drive yourself crazy, but um yeah, it's
uh it's been good. I I've enjoyed it so
far.
>> What's something that you would like
fans to understand about the rehab
process? Cuz like when when players go
through it, you know, it's kind of like
fans see it and they're like, "Oh, he'll
be back in six to nine months, but like
they're not seeing the dayto-day of it."
And I mean, I'm not seeing the day of it
day of it, but you then come back and
you know it's like, "Oh, great. He's
back." But like in that stretch where
you're going through it, like what's
something you you think maybe people
should or could maybe understand about
it?
>> Um I mean it's a long process. I think
um you know I think injuries are tough
you know for sure and and you know you
hear athletes talk about that. I think
they are they are tough but at the same
time you're training I mean it's it's
like training like you would in any
offseason. Um and now your training is
directed at you know in my case my
Achilles and and and preparing that. So,
um there are tough parts about it, but
they're tougher there are tougher
things, you know, and I think it's just
it I mean it is just a process and
sticking to that and and understanding
um where you need to be, trusting the
people around you, trusting the the
guidance you get from from them. Um but
yeah, I mean I think um I don't know
from a from a fan standpoint um you know
you see what there is on on Sundays and
getting back to the season, but um I'd
say from a rehab standpoint or just from
any offseason, there's a lot that goes
on, you know, in the offseason where
you're training, you're focusing on
things, you're trying to make small
incremental improvements and and
whatever it is. And um in my case,
that's my Achilles. there's al you know
there's a number of other things you're
working on at the same time but um yeah
I mean there's a lot going into those 17
weeks plus the postseason um and that's
you know it's a year round process
>> uh when I had you on the pod last before
the start of the season something we
talked about was the the you you said
there's genius in the simplicity of
Shane Stikens offense and the way that
he views offense and I thought about
that a lot over the first half of the
season when you know Colts are number
one in offense number one in points
scored point differential all these
things. How did that How did like
Shane's approach and then your approach
to the game lead to the success that you
guys had together last season?
>> Um, yeah. I mean, I think we had we had
good plays. You know, we had [laughter]
we had good game plans. We had um we had
stuff that that worked. you know, some
of those situations where uh Shane, the
offensive staff would say, "Hey, we
expect them to do this and here's what
it could look like and and make sure
you're ready for this and things would
play out that way." So, as a
quarterback, I think um you want to
understand the game plan. You want to
understand what they what they want you
to do, what they're expecting you to do.
Uh be able to recognize it and be able
to execute when it's there. And then
when it's not there, you know, can I
quickly make a decision that doesn't put
us put us in trouble so we can get the
next opportunity? And I think just um
practicing that, understanding that,
preparing yourself for that throughout
the week. Um you know, I I think yeah,
communication was huge. Just an
understanding of what, you know, how the
game plan was built, um the things we
were looking for, the things we didn't
like as much, and kind of how to handle
both of those situations. Is there
something is there a difference in like
how your relationship grows with with a
head coach who's a play caller in Shane
from like what you're putting together
in OTAAS and training camp and then like
when it actually works during the season
like how does that grow that
relationship or continue to build it?
Uh yeah, I mean it definitely helps um
helps that you know you have success and
um you know you see the the hard work
and a lot of the behind the-scenes stuff
pay off you know on the field and and
you get the results you want. I think
that that helps you helps everybody
helps helps build confidence and and
energizes everybody um towards the next
goal and the next opportunity. So, um,
you know, it's fun, you know, even when
things didn't work as well or, you know,
or there was a tough week or a tough
drive even or tough play. I think, um,
just the, you know, the the attitude
that, you know, we're not going to lose
confidence. We're going to keep calling
it. We're going to keep giving you
chances. We're going to keep um, you
know, I think that means a lot. Playing
quarterback, you want to feel like, you
know, you're going to keep getting shots
at it. You're going to keep getting
chances to make plays. And, um, I felt
like that. I mean, I felt like that in
training camp, you know, when I got here
and then, you know, throughout the
season and just how Shane would would
call the games, um, how he would prepare
prepare week to week. It was like, I'm
going to get some chances and if it
doesn't go great, I'm going to get
another chance and and, um, you know,
that goes a long way. the developing
trust in your pass catchers. Um, this
this is an Alec Pierce question, but
he's coming up on the pot a little bit
later and one of the plays we talked
about was that it was like a 15 yard
inbreaker against Arizona where he you
came to him like the night before the
game and said, "Hey, if they're in cover
two, I'm throwing it to you here." And
you fit that thing in like this tiny
little hole between the linebacker and I
think it was the corner.
>> Um, and he made it he you know got his
hands around made a made a plan it. Like
when you have to trust a receiver like
that to be like, "Hey, I need you in
this spot in this tiny little window and
I'm going to rip that throw, what how
does the work that you put in in OTAAS,
in, you know, those offseason throwing
sessions in training camp, how does that
lead up to that moment where you can
say, "Hey, Alec, this ball's going to
you and, you know, I trust you to go
make the play there."
>> Yeah, I mean, I think that's that's uh
largely timing. I remember we I was
sitting in before I told Alec that you
know one of me and Shane's meetings on
Saturday and and going through that
plays that play you know what if they
play cover two here are you good if I
you know if I do this and Shane you know
and Shane's like yeah of course I think
that's I think it's great and then you
look at the play there were two guys
open you know we had the end cut and
there was another guy open uh too uh but
you know just kind of that confidence
and communication that like hey Shane
has you know he he believes in it too He
he thinks that's, you know, that's a
good idea. Go for it. Rip it. So, you
come out of the fake, you hit your back
foot, and it's like you throw, you know,
it's it's there's that trust and
confidence to just let it rip. There's
confidence because, you know, Alex's
going to be in that spot and kind of all
that's led up to to letting you feel
like you can you can let it rip. And I
think that goes a long way. And and um
you know, when it's a tight window, you
got to be on time and you got to be have
that confidence to
>> to let it go. and and having the
conversations, being able to prepare for
it, uh, going in, um, having confidence
in your teammate. I mean, I think all
that is what, you know, helps helps you
be successful.
>> What excites you about the opportunity
to continue growing with Alec moving
forward.
>> Uh, yeah. I mean, he can do so much. He
can, um, you know, you guys have seen
for a number of years the plays he can
make down the field, how he can change
the game from an explosive play, deep
ball standpoint, and you saw that last
year. Um, I think he's he's the best guy
in the league at at that. And um, he can
he can do that. And then, you know, all
the other stuff too in the in the
intermediate game, the end cuts, the
crossers, the deep outs, that kind of
stuff. He he's hard. He's a hard guy to
guard one because he can run past you
and and and guys are scared of that. Um,
and then, yeah, I mean, he can do he can
do everything. So, continuing to to
feature him and get him the ball and um
he was a big- time difference maker for
us last year and and excited to uh
continue to work with him this year.
>> So, when I had Alec on the pod last
year, I asked him like, "What's
something about Daniel that might
surprise some people and he brought up
how whenever you guys were like throwing
routes over the summer that there
there's a group of like lacrosse kids
playing lacrosse and you went and you
like, "Hey, man, let me shoot some at
the net." and you you missed the net and
chucked it over like Alex's like
giggling at the thought of these kids
chasing after the ball there. [laughter]
So, now's your chance.
>> I wouldn't make I didn't make anybody go
chase the ball, but uh there were some
Duke lacrosse kids. We were in New
Jersey, I think, working out with uh
some of my Yeah. some old teammates and
stuff. And um yeah, I played lacrosse
back in the day, so I was going to let
it rip. I I missed like six in a row.
And um [laughter]
I didn't have my stick though. If I
could get my stick, I think I had a
chance. [clears throat] Um,
>> that's what I say.
>> I don't know. I don't think I've made I
I don't think I made anybody shag
lacrosse balls for me. I I don't think I
would have done that.
>> Okay. So, here's your chance to get Alec
back then. What's something you learned
about Alec Pierce that might surprise
some people?
>> He's got some interesting
interpretations of out- of- bounds rules
in golf. I think he's liberal with his
what's a lost ball, what's a [laughter]
No, I'm kidding. I think um I I don't
know. He He's a good golf I mean great
golfer [snorts] and can hammer the ball.
Um hits it a long way. Um yeah, just a a
guy. I think um fun to be around. I
think one of the one of the great parts
about
uh being here is just the the the guys
we have in the locker room and and
wanting to uh you know guys who want to
spend time together, who want to build
relationships and kind of build a team
culture. and he's been um a big part of
that. He's always a guy who wants to,
you know, good to play golf or grab
dinner or watch a football game or, you
know, I think um he's a fun guy to be
around that way and brings a lot of
people together.
>> Who's your what's your ideal like Colts
for some then? Like if you're playing to
scramble and you got to break par,
>> we got to break par. Um, I don't I'm not
sure I have much confidence in us
breaking par with I think in scramble we
should be able to, but um yeah, I mean
probably Alec, Riley.
Um,
probably Tyler, I'd say. Yeah, maybe
Tyler.
>> Yeah, that might be the foresome.
>> See, I've seen I've seen clips of Sauce
swinging a golf club.
>> Yeah, Saus is pretty good. I've seen I
haven't played with him. I've seen him
play though and seen him swing. He's got
a good looking swing.
>> It's like very fluid. Yeah,
>> which would make sense.
>> Mhm.
>> Um, you came here from, you know, spent
all this time in New York with the
Giants and I've always wondered this
like New York is such like a great food
city, right?
>> But like did you ever like go into New
York City like to grab food and like the
the question I have is like with Indie
where I always like I came from Chicago,
another great food city, but I'm like
Indy's got great restaurants if you know
where to go.
>> You kind of know where like what spots
to go to. like what do you appreciate
about Indy's food scene versus maybe
like a New York where it's I don't know
just harder to get to?
>> Yeah. Um yeah, I think I'm still still
learning a lot about the indie food
scene and trying to trying to learn all
the spots. If you got any good good uh
le, you know, off the beaten path spots,
let me know. But um yeah, I think you
know, great restaurants here downtown. I
think a number of great steak houses and
and steak spots and then uh yeah,
finding the different spots in between.
Um I think it's been it's been fun. I
mean, I think just just being out and
seeing seeing people and and uh you
know, I've really enjoyed being here in
Indie. I always say like it's a very
easy city to live in and it's very like
communal like you just kind of go
anywhere and you run into someone you
know or I'm sure for you you probably
get it a lot when you're out you know
just but like fans here are so
>> um so supportive it feels like here.
>> Yeah, absolutely. I think that's
something I realized uh early on last
year when I first got here uh and the
Pacers were going on their run and the
city was juiced and and supporting them.
Um, you know, I was like, "Wow, this,
you know, this this city really does
care about their sports teams. It's
important." Um, there's a lot of energy,
passion, intensity for for that. And,
um, makes you, you know, it's exciting.
Makes you, you know, makes you want to
be a part of it, be on the field for a
crowd and and the fans who who show that
support and appreciation. So, I've
really enjoyed being here from from that
aspect.
>> All right, I want to get you out of here
on this. Um, I'm a big Immaculate Grid
guy.
>> Okay, here we go. So, um, this one here
for our our viewers on YouTube. Um, it's
it's a grid that's got the Colts, Duke,
and Pro Football Hall of Fame up at the
top.
>> Okay.
>> And [clears throat] then, uh, the the
other ones on the left are going to be
the Giants, Notre Dame, and March
Madness. So, played in March Madness.
>> So, I'm going to give this to you here,
Daniel. And if you're listening, you can
play along. Um, just kind of put your
guesses in, think about your guesses,
say them out loud in the car. So the
goal here, Daniel, is you can't use
yourself
>> because you could use yourself on Colts
and Giants and Giants and Duke.
>> So let's start here. A player who played
for both the Indianapolis Colts and New
York Giants
>> and New York Giants.
>> Um
Jimmy Morsy.
Yeah. He was here. Yeah. Last year.
>> Yeah, he was here last year on the
practice squad.
>> All right. That see Morsy. Yeah.
>> Yeah. We'll we'll count it. This is way
better than I thought because I wrote
down a bunch of names. I'm like like
Bobby O' Carrick, Mark Lewinsky,
um Paris Campbell, if you wanted to pull
out like an Antoine Bethea.
>> Wow. There we go. I played with him my
rookie year. Yeah.
>> There you go.
>> Yeah.
>> But Jimmy Moresy, that's like Yeah.
>> Whenever you like I punch those in and
it's a load and it's like 0.003%.
>> There we go. Mory.
>> All right. Uh Giants and Duke. Giants
and Duke. Um,
Giants and Duke. Jameson Crowder was
with the Giants for a little bit.
>> Uh, Duke guy. Um, Ross Cochrell.
>> Ross Cochril
>> was also a Charlotte Latin guy. Went to
same school I went to in Charlotte. Um,
yeah, I go Ross Cochril.
>> Deion Jackson also.
>> Don Jackson. There you go.
>> And uh, Matt Skura.
>> Matt Skura. Yeah. Yeah. You could have
put Dion for uh Oh, yeah.
>> Colts and Colts and Giants, too. Yeah.
>> Uh and then Giants Hall of Fame.
>> Giants Hall of Fame.
>> Um I don't know. Lawrence Taylor.
>> Lawrence Taylor.
>> Uh yeah,
>> I would accept should be Eli Manning as
an answer, too.
>> Yeah, should be Eli.
>> All right. Um a Colts player who played
at Notre Dame.
>> Colts player who played at Notre Dame.
Uh Quinton. I mean, but that's a pretty
easy one. Nelson.
>> Spencer, right?
>> Spencer Schrader.
>> Say Spencer
>> and Blake Rupy.
>> And Blake Groupy. Um,
>> yeah.
>> You go further back. You pull out Isaac
Rochelle, too.
>> Isaac Rochelle. Okay.
>> Um, played at Notre Dame and played at
Duke.
>> That' be Riley. Riley Leonard. Probably
only one of those.
>> Probably the only one of those.
>> And, uh, Notre Dame Pro Football Hall of
Famer is kind of testing your football
history knowledge.
>> Uh, go with Joe Montana.
>> Joe Montana. Great answer. All right.
>> Okay.
>> Colts and played in March Madness. Cuz
this is going out the week of March
Madness. So, we got to we got to throw
that one in there.
>> So, [snorts] Mo, right? Mo Ali Cox.
>> Mo Ali Cox. VCU played in March Madness.
>> Okay.
>> Um, this does not need to be a football
player. So, Duke played at Duke and
played in March Madness.
>> Duke and March Madness. Uh, I'm going go
with my brother there. Bates Bates
Jones.
>> That's an incredible answer. [laughter]
I wrote down I was like Jason Tatum,
Zion Williamson, Grayson Allen, John Sh.
>> You can play to the crowd here. Go Miles
and Mason Plumbley. But your brother
being the answer.
>> My brother. Yeah, I'm going to go with
my brother. I saw him play in New
Orleans. It was final four. We lost to
Carolina on a brutal ending, but that
was uh they had a good team that year.
That was Coach K's last year. Um was
that would have been 2022 maybe or
something like that. 20 22 or three or
something.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I'm going to go give my
brother Bates right there.
>> That's incredible. Bates Jones. All
right, last one. Kind of another uh
little history test here. March Madness
and is in the Pro Football Hall of Fame.
There are four possible answers here.
>> Uh Antonio Gates.
>> Antonio Gates. He's one Kent State. They
made the Elite 8 with him.
>> The other answers would be Tony Gonzalez
with Cal, Julius Peppers at North
Carolina.
>> Julius Peppers. Yeah.
>> And then Terrell Owens at Chattanooga.
>> Okay, that's pretty good. I should got
Yeah. Julius Peppers, Carolina Panther.
Um, that's good. That's good.
>> There you go. I would say you you you
got a pretty good score there.
>> Decent. Yeah.
>> Pretty decent score.
>> Decent. Baits. Baits will definitely
help me out a lot. That would be like a
0.0000001%.
[laughter]
>> Might be the only one there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Unless you're uh your parents or
your sister's playing, too.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> All right.
>> All right. Good.
>> Well, hey, Daniel, appreciate the time
here on the podcast. Congrats again on
staying here in Indie. We're looking
forward to having you around for the
next couple years.
>> Thanks, JJ. Appreciate it.
It is my pleasure to be welcomed here on
the Colts show by wide receiver Alec
Pierce who today you just signed a new
contract with the Colts. Alec, congrats,
man. How does it feel to be staying here
in Indie?
>> Feels great. You know, this is what I
wanted. So, we're happy.
>> Um, you the the average length of an NFL
career is less than four years, right?
Like when you get into the league, it's
probably like drilled into your head
like it's hard to make it in this
league. You've made it four years and
now you've got this second contract,
which is something so many players
aspire to. Have you taken any time over
the last couple of days to kind of like
reflect on the journey that got you
here, the people that helped you get
here?
>> Yeah, for sure. I was, you know, I was
back home um these past couple days too,
Glenn Allen, Illinois. So, um that was
like just just being around there like,
you know, I drive past and see like like
the pee-wee football uh field I played
on like my high school field. I actually
ran into my high school football
coaches. It's kind of funny. Um, so I
think yeah, it's just been like just
reminiscent for sure like just of
everything that's that's gone into it
and it's been a special journey and just
excited like I feel like it's just only
the beginning. I feel like there's so
much more to do and and so much more
that's going to be added to the story.
>> I I think sometimes when players get
these, you know, second contracts,
you know, sometimes it can go one of two
ways. It can go like, you know, you you
feel like you made it. How do you view
this and and where do you feel like you
have to go now that you've kind of
reached this this point in your career?
>> Yeah, I think now it's all about
the team and being the best team we can
become. You know, like I think
I haven't had a opportunity in the four
years I've been in the league to go to
the playoffs. I think it's it's there's
a lot of things as a team like we need
to win the division. There's so many
things um on in that route that I feel
like I have not accomplished at all. So,
um, that's going to be that's obviously
always the goal, you know, but I think
now for me, like that is like like the
sole goal, you know, win games. What can
we do to to to bring a championship back
to Indianapolis?
>> How does that drive your like off
season, the work you put in? Just kind
of that that goal of like, let's bring a
championship, but let's win the
division, let's make the playoffs. Like,
how does that is that like in the back
of your head as you're lifting,
training, doing any of those things?
Like, how do you use that as motivation?
Yeah, I think I think the biggest thing
would be like
um just developing like the
relationships within like you know guys
on the team and stuff. So like in the
offseason
I I know how important it'll be to be
with my quarterback and to be um just
you know with other guys especially guys
on the offense and stuff, you know, get
together with with Josh DS and and uh
Tyler Warren and and Daniel Jones, you
know, guys like that. Let's all work
together and and work on, you know,
becoming the best players we can be
individually. but but together so we all
get better as a team.
>> What does it mean to you to be able to
play with Daniel now going forward?
>> That's so special. That that's that was
like my biggest thing I was harping on
in throughout this whole process like
you know I'm I'm not talking to the the
the front office or anything like that
but I was telling my agents I'm like hey
make sure you tell them like like Daniel
Jones like this is a quarterback I want
to play with. like that. That was
something and they knew for like
negotiations um and and stuff like that.
Like
it, you know, it's it's hard for for me
to commit to a team without a
quarterback in place. So, like they were
they were working on Daniel stuff um in
the beginning and that was kind of
always like they're like we got to get
this done and then um yeah cuz I cuz I
not not cuz I express that. I know they
want him obviously clearly but yeah I uh
Daniel's been a special quarterback to
play with and somebody I believe in you
know completely. So um I I know we can
be we can be great with him at
quarterback.
>> What what about him makes him special as
a quarterback? Yeah, I think the, you
know, I think the the way he approaches
like the week and just preparation and
stuff like that, I think he's just so
ready to go for Sunday. Um, and I think
he completely understands the the the
game plan and the other team we're
playing, like the scouting report, stuff
like that. I think that's like really
where he kind of, you know, gets himself
a little bit ahead. And then obviously
he's got the skill set, he's got the
athleticism, the ability to make all the
throws. Um
and I think that leadership aspect just
like with the preparation I think it um
fuels into everybody and everybody you
know kind of leans into that and and can
can learn from that
>> is that just like you know everyone's
kind of pulling in the same direction
with him kind of leading it.
>> Yeah.
>> Up there.
>> Yeah. And I think I think too when you
feel prepared um it it builds
confidence. It brings confidence. So I
think you walk out on the field feeling
like ready to go and then you're that's
a confident team and a confident team is
a hard team to beat.
>> How did he help your game? cuz like you
you've talked a little bit on like other
podcasts about like kind of expanding
your you know your route tree and
expanding the routes that you're
getting. Like the one throw I thought
about
>> uh was the the one against Arizona
>> where you run that kind of as like a 15
yard dig
>> and he puts that thing like almost
behind you
>> but the linebacker is like roboting out
to to go make a play on it and he puts
it like in this tiny little window
>> that you're able to make a catch. Like
how did he help you maybe grow in that
area last year? So that you couldn't
have asked about a better play because
that play is the example of of like
really what I'm saying with Daniel in
preparation. So like we always get
together, we meet I think it's like
Saturday night. I think it's what the
like the last second before the games,
but he kind of goes over some film and
some plays that are on like the play
sheet and like certain looks like what
he's thinking and just hearing kind of
like that quarterback mindset. So, that
was one play right there. And I remember
him saying like the play not necessarily
like never went to me in practice. Um,
we had Josh on some type of like kind of
double move like like wheel route. No,
I'm setting up the the inb breakaker
hoping to uh grab the coverage and then
send Josh kind of get him isolated on
linebacker and then go deep on him. Um,
and Daniel told me he's like, "Hey, if
it's cover two, like you're my answer."
And he just said that. That was just
like that quick little sentence. And
then in the game I get out there and you
know quarterback tries to put some hands
on me, doesn't run with me. See the
safety over the top. I'm like, "Oh, it's
cover two right here."
>> And yeah, cuz I barely got my head
around to catch the ball. But like I
knew as soon as I got the guy as soon as
I saw cover two right away,
>> I knew then I was like, "Oh, this ball
probably is going to come to me." Like
he said in the meetings like um and if I
don't think if he would have said I
don't think if he would have said that,
I don't think I would have got my head
around and caught the ball cuz it was
literally caught like the back half of
the ball. like I don't think I could
have been any later getting my eyes
around and catching it. So,
>> um stuff like that, just the preparation
and just being on the same page and
communicating well, like that's special.
That's what you need between the
quarterback and and his receivers.
>> The the other one I thought about was
that kind of it was like a drag rot you
ran on that third and six against the
Broncos.
>> Yeah.
>> Where you you're kind of face up on
Certan,
>> you beat him and you just kind of run,
but Daniel like buys just enough time
with that pass rush to get the ball to
you. Yeah. like those are plays too
where he clearly trusted you just kind
of like right from the jump last year.
How did that kind of develop?
>> Yeah, I think um I think he trusted all
of us receivers, you know. I think he
knew he knew like what we knew what we
needed to do on the certain plays like
that play right there like that was
that's a mesh concept. It's man-to-man
coverage. Like
>> I'm the guy he's going to come to on
that. Like he's probably checking the
like the running back then to me. And um
so I knew I'm going to get lined up. I
see I I recognize man coverage. I know I
got to run this route to win there. Um
same goes with I think it was probably
Josh or Tyler on the other side.
>> It was Josh. Yeah.
>> Yeah. They know, okay, like it's
man-to-man coverage. I got to try to get
some type of interference, you know, at
least make the guy like
>> like run run run like run around me or
something like that. So, um, yeah, like
I think we all just I think he the
confidence comes and and he he knows
that we know what we got to do and he
trusts that we can all win win against
man coverage. Um, so I think he he's
confident and trusting all of us.
>> One other one about Daniel. When I had
you on the pod last September, I asked
you like what's something about Daniel
that might surprise people that you've
learned about him? And you said every
time he you're you're like you throw
some routes. uh if there's kids playing
lacrosse, he'll grab a lacrosse stick
and he'll like whip the ball, but it
always goes way over the net. And you
were just like giggling about these kids
chasing after the ball that
>> Yeah, that was that was funny.
>> Um
>> Yeah.
>> What's something else you learned about
him? Maybe like seeing how he went
through last year with the the highs of
the first 10 games to, you know, the
lows of dealing with this broken leg to
the Achilles. Like what's something else
you maybe learned about him last year?
Yeah, I think I learned, you know, how
great of a teammate he is. Um, how much
he cares about all of us. Like I think
seeing him like especially with like
Riley Leonard is like a great example.
Like the last game like I know he cared
probably so much about how well Rally
could do there and like he was in there
helping him prepare doing everything he
could cuz he's he really want you know
he wants everyone to succeed. He wants
everyone to do well. Um, and like I, you
know, and you could say that game for
our team, like we already out the
playoffs, so I guess it like for the
team that really didn't matter for a
whole lot, but I think he just knew like
like this is so important for Riley. And
um, so I think just just seeing that
like seeing how much she really cares
and wants all of us to do great. I think
>> in that game, were you like, "Oh my god,
was my last moment as a Colt getting
ejected?"
>> Did that cross your mind?
>> Yeah, that that would have been a crazy
way to go out. That's why I had to come
back here, you I can't can't end on
that.
>> It wasn't.
>> What's up?
>> Thank goodness it wasn't.
>> Thank goodness it wasn't. Right.
>> Um, do you know what the most like
mileage you've ever ran in a game is?
>> Do you?
>> No, I don't. I wish I did, but
>> Yeah,
>> cuz you you you do run a lot of these
vertical routes whether you're getting
the ball or not.
>> There's some good cardio out there.
>> Yeah. Right. Like, how do you train for
that? Because like we we can look at it
and say, "Oh, he probably just runs on a
treadmill." But like you're also getting
jammed by a cornerback. You've got to be
blocking in the run game. It's not just
as simple as like you just run a bunch.
>> Yeah. Um Yeah. You just got to you just
got to stay in shape, you know? Like I I
try not to ever really get out of shape.
Like I I'll take some time off like
um like I'm not like necessarily working
on football and stuff like that, but I'm
still like finding ways like getting on
a bike or like finding ways to get the
heart rate up and just keep your body
just in in shape, you know?
>> I mean because like soccer players run a
ton. Um, but it's just it's a different
kind of running and I don't know just
like the the physicality that comes with
all that running.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I guess how do you prepare your
body for the physicality of an NFL
season? Is there a way you can do it in
terms of like training?
>> Yeah, I think
>> got to get through training camp or
>> Yeah. I I try to just get my body like
moving functionally as as good as it can
going into the season knowing that
there's going to be some injuries that
happen. There's going to be some things
that get your body off of that, right?
So that's like what really I'd say the
offseason especially like to like this
point it's more so about just getting
like like almost physical therapy type
work and and getting your body just
moving as functioning as well as
possible because
>> when you do have something off and
you're you're not like moving the right
way, you know, then that that's when you
start having other injuries. And that's
kind of what you'll see like during the
season like oh it might be minor but say
you got you got tackled and you got
rolled up and your ankle's not great,
right? and then you start getting off a
little bit and you're and you're you're
you're breaking down only on the other
leg and stuff like that and then it's
like you have an injury like a like a
worse injury on that side. So like I
always just try to make sure like can we
get everything back to how it moving and
working how it should be because like we
don't want to be you know
>> just um like favoring anything. Yeah.
>> All right, let's pivot here. Give me the
big brother scouting report on Kaden
Pierce.
>> The big brother scouting. Okay. Kade.
Cade is a Kade is a gritty basketball
player. He like he's a guy you want on
your team like no matter what team. Like
I always talk about this like you think
about if you ask like you know the top
five basketball players of all time like
NBA players like it's like looking at
the um like the the Olympic team, you
know, like you got to have a guy out
there. It might not be the the the
you're not just going to go, "Oh, these
are the top five guys who score the most
points a game." You know what I mean?
Like you need guys who fill certain
roles. And Cade is the type of guy like
he's he's like a double double type guy.
Like he's going to get rebounds, he's
going to play defense, he'll score
points, but like I know I think his game
is um really like complimentary. And I
think it's like I think it's cuz he's
he's always grown up playing with um so
Braden Huff went to our high school
who's at Gonzaga.
>> Yeah. So he's grown up he's he's grown
up always playing with like a like he
was never just it was never just like
him and you know four other guys out
there that that weren't at his level
like he always played his whole I think
his whole college or high school team
went D1 so the whole starting lineup so
he's like learned he's always played
good basketball and played team
basketball so I think he that's what his
biggest thing like he really understands
that team basketball and he can I think
he's a guy you can kind of plug into
like any starting lineup and like he's
going to add value because you need a
guy like that. You know,
>> everyone around here is like you're
either a Purdue fan or an Indiana fan.
>> I mean, can you like tow both lines or
because your little brother's at Purdue
now, do you have just be like, "Boiler
up, baby." You know, like what do you
what do you have to do?
>> I mean, yeah. For for basketball, for
basketball, I'm going to be a Purdue fan
for sure. You know, it's not I'm not
going to be like the the Purdue fan that
hates IU, you know? Like, Right.
>> Like I like I don't you know, I hope IU
does well too, but like when Purdue's
playing, I'm I'm gonna win Purdue to
win, you I mean, can you envision
yourself going up to, you know, games?
>> Oh, yeah. I already told him. I was
like, "You got to like let me know if we
can get like some like some some season
tickets there or what?" Like, I'm going
to be every time I can go there, I'm
going to be there. So,
>> I told your dad like the the Pierce
family is probably in the top 1% of
commuters on I 65.
>> Yeah. Got to be next year. So,
>> got to be, right?
>> Um, all right. Last one for you, and I
got a little bit of trivia here.
>> Okay.
>> Who is the five fastest 40-yard dash
times currently on the Colts roster?
I think I saw you guys post this the
other day and
>> see this wasn't a test to see if you
were paying to our social med pay paying
attention to our social media
team over there.
>> Veronica and Bri back there.
>> Let's go. Um
yeah, I think I saw like so like Nick
Cross isn't on the roster right now.
Right. Right. So
>> because I know Nick was fast. It might
be
Anthony Gould.
>> Anthony Gold 439 tied for number one.
tied for number one with maybe like a
corner like maybe like uh
uh who is it? It's a quarterback, right?
>> It's not a cornerback.
>> It's not a quarterback.
Uh or safety.
>> It's not a safety.
>> It's a offense. It's a receiver.
>> It is It is not a receiver.
>> Is it a running back?
>> It is a running back. Jonathan Taylor.
It's Jonathan Taylor.
>> You're on 149. Yeah. JT JT and Cold ran
43 nines.
>> Okay.
>> Number three is a quarterback.
>> Okay. Um,
>> this is the one where I was like, if you
pull this one out, this will be
this will be impressive.
>> Oh man.
>> He's on the team he did not play last
year.
>> He was hurt.
>> Yeah,
>> he's on his team. didn't play Wally.
>> Yeah. Justin Wall-E.
>> Wall-ally
>> who's a 44.
>> Yeah.
>> And then Tide Sauce
>> 441.
>> You You got it. 441.
>> I was a faster 441 though. I don't know
if they like they did. You guys put that
on the the graphic
>> that you were you guys put me ahead.
>> How are you a faster 441?
>> We're just going to say that it was a
faster.
>> You're the one sitting here right now.
Well,
>> I only ran one time. So So I think we're
going to call it just faster because
like we'll say his like say he ran it
twice. I don't know if he ran twice, but
it averages to slower. You know,
>> he did have a better 10 yard split. Does
that matter?
>> That just means I'm fast. Actually,
faster than him in the long in the long.
>> That's a great point.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Do you know why it's a 40-yard dash?
>> No idea.
>> Punt coverage.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know why.
>> It was invented in the 1940s
by Paul Brown, who was the coach of the
Cleveland Browns, because 40 yards was
roughly the average distance players
would have to travel to cover a punt.
>> So, there you go.
>> It's pretty smart and practical. Yeah,
>> it is smart and practical. But that
means like why do the O lineman do it
and why do the you know think about it.
>> It's a great great question.
>> Yeah.
>> I think Tanner Bordellini might have the
fastest 40 of any O lineman on the team.
>> Yeah, he's fast.
>> I think he's like a good athlete. Yeah.
>> Anyways, let's get you out of here on
that. Alec, congratulations. Appreciate
the time, man.
>> The Colt Show is presented by Microsoft
Surface Co-Pilot Plus PC, where every
day is game day. Greatness in the NFL
starts long before kickoff. It's built
in the quiet hours of preparation and
the discipline to turn insights into
action. The Indianapolis Colts rely on
Microsoft Surface Co-Pilot Plus PCs to
turn preparation into performance. With
real time AI powered insights right on
the sideline, coaches and players can
make smarter, faster decisions when it
matters most. From the field to the
front office, Microsoft Surface Co-Pilot
Plus PCs are transforming how the
Indianapolis Colts prepare, strategize,
and win. This isn't just about football.
It's about unlocking potential wherever
the game is played. Hey Colts fans, the
Colts Sunday night 7 on seven series is
returning. Boys tackle and dedicated
girls flag can train in an open gym
format across select Sundays this
winter. Presented by Forte Sports
Medicine and Orthopedics with support
from Gatorade and the Grid Iron
Foundation. Sign up now at
colts.comsnon7.